In this chapter we'll remind you all the basics required for a better understanding of a wireless transmission.
For that, we will talk about the unit, the decibel, as it might be a new topic for some of you.
We'll discuss its interest and its use.
We will then introduce the terms dBm, RSSI, sensitivity, transmitted power, received power and link
budget.
And finally, we will talk about the influence of noise in LoRa transmission and how LoRa achieved
to transmit data when noise become much higher
than the data itself.
With all these notions we'll be much more comfortable with technical documentation when it comes to discuss
about the performances of a transceiver.